<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alice in Dataland</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Alice in Dataland</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; Alice Milivinti 2018 powered by Hugo, Pickles</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>COVID-19: Unemployment and Income Supports</title>
      <link>/posts/covid-19-unemployment-and-income-supports/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/covid-19-unemployment-and-income-supports/</guid>
      <description>This is a collaboration with Rebecca Hasdell and David Rehkopf.
Data Sources: Census Current Population Survey (CPS) Source files available: https://github.com/alice1020/COVID-unemployment-and-income-supports
Data come from the Current Population Survey, which have been download from: https://cps.ipums.org/cps/index.shtml (registration required).
The codebooks for the extraction are the files:
Core_2020_Extr_Codebook.xml for the core set of questions for monthly samples from 01-2019 to 04-2020. Variables selected: YEAR, SERIAL, MONTH, HWTFINL, CPSID, ASECFLAG, PERNUM, WTFINL, CPSIDP, EMPSTAT, LABFORCE, OCC, CLASSWKR, UHRSWORKT, UHRSWORK1, UHRSWORK2, AHRSWORKT, AHRSWORK1, AHRSWORK2, EARNWT, HOURWAGE, PAIDHOUR, EARNWEEK, UHRSWORKORG, WKSWORKORG.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Spatio-Temporal Analysis of Migration</title>
      <link>/posts/a-spatio-temporal-analysis-of-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/a-spatio-temporal-analysis-of-migration/</guid>
      <description>I know, the title sounds intriguing boring and in effect it is. When I started my PhD I did not even know what spatial statistics exactly was. It was my inspiring colleague, Dr. Giacomo Benini, who introduced me to that. My PhD is in Demography, more precisely on migration studies. So why should not I apply some spatial statistics to human migration movements? Most of the time I think I have come up with a brilliant idea someone else has already had it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Alice and if I have to describe myself in one line I would say that I get bored quickly and I like to question everything (I am a woman, you know).
Linear career paths are not my cup of tea. I was not born with a specific dream. When I was little I did not want to become a doctor, even though some family members have tried to push me into that, or an astronaut.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>